- question: "What command would you use to recall your previous commands?"
  answers:
    - "recall"
    - "history"
    - "ls"
    - "double tab"
  correct: "history"
  day: 2

- question: "What command would you use to list the contents of a directory?"
  answers:
    - "tab"
    - "cd"
    - "ls"
    - "touch"
  correct: "ls"
  day: 2

- question: "What command would you use to delete a file?"
  answers:
    - "delete"
    - "remove"
    - "rm"
    - "right-click then delete <-- (hint THIS IS LINUX, we do NOT click here! :)"
  correct: "rm"
  day: 2

- question: "You are working on a problem and realize that you need to watch the logs in real time, what command will you use?"
  answers:
    - "watch"
    - "say linux-wan-kenobi, you are my only hope"
    - "tail -f"
    - "vim   /var/log/syslog"
  correct: "tail -f"
  day: 2

- question: "You need to connect to a remote host, so you decide to use SSH and there is no .ssh/config file. Which command is the correct format?"
  answers:
    - "ssh bender@10.10.2.3 -i ~/.ssh/id_rsa"
    - "ssh bender@10.10.2.3 "
    - "ssh bender"
    - "ssh 10.10.2.3"
  correct: "ssh bender@10.10.2.3 -i ~/.ssh/id_rsa"
  day: 2

- question: "You need to move an entire directory of content to a remote host, which utility is best suited for this?"
  answers:
    - "ssh"
    - "scp"
    - "rsync"
    - "megasync"
    - "click and drag (hint- In Linux, we do NOT click and drag :)"
  correct: "rsync"
  day: 2

- question: "You need to have multiple bash sessions open, what tool will you use?"
  answers:
    - "many putty windows (ahhh please do NOT go for this one)"
    - "tmux"
    - "bash"
    - "vim"
  correct: "tmux"
  day: 2

- question: "What is this character called and what does it do? \"|\""
  answers:
    - "bar, and is used for comparisons"
    - "pipe, and used for directing outputs from one program to the input of another"
    - "redirect, and used to redirect I/O"
    - "This character is never used in Linux."
  correct: "pipe, and used for directing outputs from one program to the input of another"
  day: 3

- question: "What command is used to change the owner of a file?"
  answers:
    - "owner"
    - "chown"
    - "chmod"
    - "touch"
  correct: "chown"
  day: 3

- question: "What is a dependency in Linux?"
  answers:
    - "Software necessary to support the software you want to run"
    - "A permissions error"
    - "Not handled with apt, dnf, or yum installations"
    - "The Linux kernel"
  correct: "Software necessary to support the software you want to run"
  day: 3

- question: "What

 is UGO in Linux? (choose two)"
  answers:
    - "Permission categories"
    - "user, group, and ... owner?"
    - "broken down further into read, write, and execute"
    - "Describe the owner of the file"
  correct:
    - "Permission categories"
    - "broken down further into read, write, and execute"
  day: 3

- question: "What command would you use to find all files the begin with \"host\", starting from the root directory?"
  answers:
    - "find / -name hosts"
    - "find / -name hosts*"
    - "tree -f hosts*"
    - "ls hosts*"
  correct: "find / -name hosts*"
  day: 3